Guide to the Harris J. Ryan Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Harris J. Ryan papers
1899-1934
SC1034
Ryan, Harris J. (Harris Joseph), 1866-1934.
0.75 Linear feet
Collection includes syllabi and notes on alternators, synchronous motors, transformers, transmission lines and other topics, 1899-1917; correspondence regarding a lecture tour of Japan, 1930-32; Harris' articles and publications, 1911-31; articles and clippings on the Ryan high voltage lab; and biographical information and bibliographies.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1965.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Harris J. Ryan was a professor of electrical engineering at Stanford (1905-1931; emeritus, 1931-1934), head of the Department of Electrical Engineering and first director of the Ryan High Voltage Laboratory.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes syllabi and notes on alternators, synchronous motors, transformers, transmission lines and other topics, 1899-1917; correspondence regarding a lecture tour of Japan, 1930-32; Harris' articles and publications, 1911-31; articles and clippings on the Ryan high voltage lab; guest book from the lab; and biographical information and bibliographies.
Access Terms
Ryan, Harris J. (Harris Joseph), 1866-1934.; Stanford University. Department of Electrical Engineering. Faculty.; Stanford University. Ryan High Voltage Laboratory.; Electrical engineering --California.; Electronics.
Collection Contents
- Syllabi on alternators, 1899-1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Syllabi on synchronous motors, 1908-1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Syllabi on syn. [rotary] converters, 1907-1912 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Syllabi on transformers, 1907-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Syllabi on induction motors, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Syllabi on transmission lines, 1908-1915 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Syllabi on skin effect and circuit breakers, 1907-1912 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Biography (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bibliography (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence regarding a lecture tour of Japan, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Patent, assignment of rights to General Electric, 1938; and miscellaneous notes (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Permit for the still used in High Voltage Laboratory (from United States Prohibition Service) with cover letter, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Articles on High Voltage Lab, 1929, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Articles by others on the High Voltage Lab (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Publications, 1911-1927 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Publications, 1903-1923 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ryan High Voltage Lab Guest book, 1920-1931 (Box 2, Folder 2)
General note
Personal mementoes of Harris J. Ryan can be found in the Stanford Archives Museum Collection under the call number AM 2010-006.